The only reward of virtue is virtue; the only way to have a friend is to be one.
对美德的回报是美德，获得友谊的唯一途径是给人以友谊。
------------------------------------
把人民放在最高的地位
put people in the most prominent place in our hearts.

 一切国家机关工作人员，无论身居多高的职位，都必须牢记我们的共和国是中华人民共和国，始终要把人民放在心中最高的位置，始终全心全意为人民服务，始终为人民利益和幸福而努力工作。

No matter how high a position one holds, all personnel of state organs should keep firmly in mind that our republic is the People's Republic of China, and we should always put the people in the most prominent place in our hearts, always serve the people wholeheartedly, and always work hard for the people's interests and happiness.


人民是真正的英雄
People are the real heroes.

人民是历史的创造者，人民是真正的英雄。
People are the creators of history. They are the real heroes.

波澜壮阔的中华民族发展史是中国人民书写的！
The magnificent history of the development of the Chinese nation was written by the Chinese people.

博大精深的中华文明是中国人民创造的！
The extensive Chinese civilization was created by the Chinese people.

历久弥新的中华民族精神是中国人民培育的！
The unfading spirit of the Chinese nation is cultivated by the Chinese people.

中华民族迎来了从站起来、富起来到强起来的伟大飞跃是中国人民奋斗出来的！
The development of the Chinese nation - from standing up for itself, to enriching itself, to getting stronger - is made possible because of the Chinese people.

要幸福就要奋斗
Happiness comes out of arduous work.
 中国人民自古就明白，世界上没有坐享其成的好事，要幸福就要奋斗。
Since ancient times, the Chinese people have realized that in the world there is no such thing as sitting idle and enjoying all the benefits. Happiness comes out of arduous work.

四分五裂的国家不可能发展进步
A fragmented nation will never enjoy development.

中国人民从亲身经历中深刻认识到，团结就是力量，团结才能前进，一个四分五裂的国家不可能发展进步。
From our own experience, the Chinese people have come to realize that unity is power, and unity will take us forward. A fragmented nation will never enjoy development.

路再长，走下去，定能到达
However long the journey is, if you keep walking, you will certainly arrive at your destination.

中国人民相信，山再高，往上攀，总能登顶；路再长，走下去，定能到达。
The Chinese people believe that however high the mountain is, if you keep climbing, you will come to the summit. However long the journey is, if you keep walking, you will certainly arrive at your destination.

时间不等人，容不得有半点懈怠
Time waits for no man.

把蓝图变为现实，是一场新的长征。路虽然还很长，但时间不等人，容不得有半点懈怠。
Translating the blueprint into reality will be a new Long March. The road ahead will be very long, but time waits for no man.

我们决不能安于现状、贪图安逸、乐而忘忧，必须不忘初心、牢记使命、奋发有为，努力创造属于新时代的光辉业绩！
We should not in the slightest slacken(['slækən] 减缓；（使）变得松弛) our efforts, and we should by no means rest on our laurels(['lɔrəl] 荣誉；赞誉) and seek comfort while losing sight of potential problems. We should always bear in mind what we have set out for, and redouble ([.ri'dʌb(ə)l] 加倍；增加；加强)our efforts to achieve greater achievements in the new era.

把人民拥护不拥护作为衡量一切工作得失的根本标准
What the people advocate, what the people approve and accept must be the sole measurement of all of our work. 

 把人民拥护不拥护、赞成不赞成、高兴不高兴、答应不答应作为衡量一切工作得失的根本标准，着力解决好人民最关心最直接最现实的利益问题，让全体中国人民和中华儿女在实现中华民族伟大复兴的历史进程中共享幸福和荣光！
What the people advocate, what the people approve and accept must be the sole measurement of all of our work. We must be committed to addressing(=cope with) the most direct and realistic interests of the people that they are most concerned about. So that all the Chinese people and the generations to come in China will enjoy happiness and glory from such a process of realizing the great rejuvenation(rɪˈʤuːvəˌneɪʃən) of the Chinese nation.

一切分裂祖国的行径和伎俩注定要失败
Any actions and tricks to split China are doomed to fail.

一切分裂祖国的行径和伎俩都是注定要失败的，都会受到人民的谴责和历史的惩罚！
Any actions and tricks to split China are doomed to fail. And these separatists' actions will be met with the condemnation of the people and the punishment of history.

中国人民有坚定的意志、充分的信心、足够的能力挫败一切分裂国家的活动！
Chinese people have the resolve, the confidence, and the ability to defeat secessionist([sɪˈsef(ə)nɪst] a.赞成脱离主义的/n.脱离论者) attempts in any form.

中国人民和中华民族有一个共同信念，这就是：我们伟大祖国的每一寸领土都绝对不能也绝对不可能从中国分割出去！
The Chinese people and the Chinese nation have a shared conviction: not one single inch of our land will be and can be seceded{[sɪ'sid] 退出} from China.

人间自有公道在！
 Justice will finally prevail.

只有那些习惯于威胁他人的人，才会把所有人都看成是威胁。对中国人民为人类和平与发展作贡献的真诚愿望和实际行动，任何人都不应该误读，更不应该曲解。人间自有公道在！
Only those who are given to threatening other people will perceive other people as a threat. The Chinese people's aspiration and sincerity in actions to contribute to mankind's peace and development should not be misinterpreted（[.mɪsɪn'tɜrprət] 误解）, much less be distorted（[dɪ'stɔrt] 曲解；使歪扭；使不正常；） by anyone. Justice will finally prevail.


新时代属于每一个人
The new era belongs to each and every one of us

新时代属于每一个人，每一个人都是新时代的见证者、开创者、建设者。只要精诚团结、共同奋斗，就没有任何力量能够阻挡中国人民实现梦想的步伐！
The new era belongs to each and every one of us, and everyone of us is part of this new era, witnessing, blazing new trails and building this new era. As long as we remain united, work hard together, nothing can stop us from achieving the Chinese dream by the Chinese people. 