flattery [n]阿谀奉承

be hell-bent to sth.不顾一切地

half-baked [a.]半成熟的

confer [kən'fɜr]
~ (with sb) (on/about sth)
商讨；协商；交换意见

~ sth (on/upon sb)
授予，颁发（奖项、学位、荣誉或权利）

suffice [sə'faɪs] [vi]
suffice (it) to say (that)…
无须多说；只需说…就够了
suffice to do sth.
-----------------------------
senior manager 高级经理；高管

Straight-A student 学霸
①普通版：straight A student 
②种族版：straight A-sian student 
③崇拜版：straight A-mazing student 
④羡慕嫉妒恨版：straight A-hole student 
⑤腹黑诅咒版：straight A-lone forever student 
⑥非人类版：straight A-lien student
-----------------------------
somone’s cup of tea某人的一杯茶。代表正中下怀，正中口味的意思.
例句： You are just my cup of tea.你就是我的那杯茶，你就是我喜欢的人。

cuppa=a cup of tea英式英语里常见的一种说法。
例句：Would you like a cuppa？ 你要不要喝杯茶？

for all the tea in China所有在中国的茶。那这个短语的意思是说如论如何的意思。
not for例句: I wouldn't do it for all the tea in China.  我无论如何都不会做这件事的.

a storm in a teacup 小题大做的意思。
例句：The couple next door are always arguing but it is usually a storm in a teacup. 隔壁的夫妇经常吵架，但多数是小题大做。

-----------------------------
peculiar /pɪˈkjuːljɚ/ 怪异的
1.not usual or normal : strange 
It seems peculiar that he would leave town and not tell anybody.
2.peculiar to 
: of, relating to, or found in (only one person, thing, or place) 
a custom peculiar to America [=a custom that is found only in America]
3.peculiarly [adv.] 
The movie has a peculiarly [=distinctively, uniquely, particularly] American quality.
-----------------------------

concert season 音乐季

self-assured == confident

foretell 预告

court room 法庭；审判室

a skillful closing argument
（=summing up/ conclusion statement）
巧妙的结案陈词
jury trial

fallen victim to sth. 得了...的受害者
syndrome 综合症
---------------------------------
repository US[rɪ'pɑzə.tɔri]
n. 存库

physical currency 实际货币
cheques 支票
paper money 纸币
electronic payment 电子支付
essential purchases 基本购物


chronically 慢性地
slums n.平民窟
overlap n.v.重复
illiterate a.文盲的
fertility 生产力
demography 人口统计学
light bulbs 灯泡
intervene 插入；介入
address the problem 解决问题
gut 肠道；消化道
non-human species 非人类物种
rule of thumb 经验法则