theater company 剧社；剧团

well aware 清楚地认识到
---well 还可以加其他动词，构成好的搭配，详情请看搭配词典。

decipher vt.详解

dusty a.充满灰尘的

dull a.呆滞的，无趣的。

day-to-day 注意to 弱读 每天的

sonnets 十四行诗

film vt.把...拍成电影

the tech savvy 精通技术的人

shoot film/photograph 拍摄；摄影

crew 工作人员

Brooklyn 布鲁克林区（在美国纽约）

dark wood 黑木（黑暗森林）

cash register
---A cash register, also referred to as a till（收银台,放钱的抽屉） in the United Kingdom and other Commonwealth(英联邦) countries, is a mechanical or electronic device for registering and calculating transactions at a point of sale.

------------China Daily-------------

two sessons 两会
在现代化进程中，很多传统正在逐渐消失
Many traditions are rapidly vanishing amid modernization.

非物质文化遗产 intangible cultural heritages

Go 有围棋的意思
云南永子围棋非遗传承人
inheritor of Yunnan Yongzi Go 

周淑英剪纸艺术馆馆长
Curator[kjə'reɪtər] of Zhou Shuying Paper-cut Art Gallery

把非物质文化遗产纳入教学体系
incorporating into the teaching system

make deliberations 深思熟虑

pillar 柱子->中流砥柱

at rock bottom 最低水平
---rock-bottom price 最低价
---rock-bottom interest rates 最低利率

picky 挑剔的

精准扶贫 advanced targeted poverty alleviation 

消除极端贫困 eliminate/alleviate extreme poverty 

农村金融的立法 legislation of rural-financice 

金融机构 finance agencies 

农村地区的医疗状况 medical condition in rural areas

生存状况 living condition 

科技成果 scientific achievement

传统中医药 traditional chinese medical herbs 

大量机会 vibrant opportunities 

掌握科技 grasp the technology

academician（[ə.kædə'mɪʃ(ə)n]） 院士；学者

因地制宜 adjust measures to local conditions

空闲土地 unused land 

深化脱贫工作 intensify poverty alleviation

人的全面发展 well-rounded human development

共同富裕和繁荣 common prosperity for everyone

“我宣誓：忠于中华人民共和国宪法，维护宪法权威，履行法定职责，忠于祖国、忠于人民，恪尽职守、廉洁奉公，接受人民监督，为建设富强民主文明和谐美丽的社会主义现代化强国努力奋斗！”
"I pledge my allegiance ([ə'lidʒəns] 效忠；拥戴) to the Constitution of the People's Republic of China (PRC) to safeguard the Constitution authority, fulfil my legal obligations([.ɑblɪ'ɡeɪʃ(ə)n] 义务；责任；), be loyal to the country and the people, be committed ([kəˈmɪtɪd] 忠诚的)and honest in my duty, accept the people's supervision([.supər'vɪʒ(ə)n] 监督) and work for a great moder0n socialist country that is prosperous, strong, democratic, culturally advanced, harmonious, and beautiful!"

一代人有一代人的长征路。
Generation has its own long march trail. 

------------------------------------

verse [vɜrs] n.诗歌 
versed a. 精通的
--versed in sth.
seasoned a.经验丰富的
barman n.酒吧间男招待
lest 唯恐；以免
toss n/v. 投掷
shot glass 酒杯
a shot of liquor 一杯酒

intrigue 
[t][oftpass]~sb.it intrigues sb that… 激起…的兴趣；引发…的好奇心
[i]~ (with sb) (against sb)秘密策划（加害他人）；密谋

locale [ləʊˈkæl] n.现场；〈正式〉(小说发生或电影拍摄的)场所

tie in 连接在；合乎